eurostemcell.org 2017-12-22

# Privacy and Cookies | Eurostemcell

## Our privacy policy

**The information we collect about you, our security agreement and your rights.**

The University of Edinburgh ( **the “University** ”, “us” or “we”) is committed to preserving your privacy. Please read the following privacy policy to understand how we use and protect the information obtained from those visiting and using the EuroStemCell website [www.eurostemcell.org](http://www.eurostemcell.org/) and its subdomains (the “website”).

By using the EuroStemCell website you consent to the collection, retention and use of your personal information in accordance with the terms of this policy.

### Information we collect

  * Personal details (such as your name, contact details and email address) which you provide by registering with us or submitting an enquiry via the website.
  * Your responses to surveys which we ask you to complete for research purposes.
  * How you use the website and any other information you post, email or otherwise send to us.

### Cookies

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of the website. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that is stored on your device. The cookies set may obtain information about you, your computer, your use of our website and your general internet usage.   
[More about cookies](http://www.eurostemcell.org/privacy-cookies#cookies).

### IP addresses

We may collect information where available about your IP address, operating system and browser type.  This is data about users' browsing actions and patterns.  It is used to inform improvements to the website, for system administration, and to report aggregate information to third parties.

### Security

We employ security measures to protect your information from access by unauthorised persons and against unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction or damage.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is never completely secure.  Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal or other data transmitted to our website.  Any transmission is at your own risk.  Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to prevent unauthorised access.

### Your rights

You have the right to ask for a copy of the information held by us in our records in return for which we charge a small fee. 

If any information held by us is incorrect, you have the right to ask for this to be corrected and updated.  Please help us keep our records updated by informing us of any changes to your email address and other contact details. 

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes.  We will usually inform you (before collecting your personal data) if we intend to use your personal data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes.  You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your personal data.  You can also exercise the right at any time by [contacting us](http://www.eurostemcell.org/contact).

### Third party websites

The website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of third parties. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.  Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these third party websites.

### Changes to our Privacy Policy

We may amend this policy from time to time.  If we make any substantial changes we will notify you by posting a prominent notice on the website.

### Make an enquiry

If you have any queries concerning the information we hold about you or this privacy policy, or any questions on our use of your information then please [contact us](http://www.eurostemcell.org/contact).

## How we use your information

**How we use your information, how it is stored and the circumstances under which we disclose data.**

We use your information to:

  * enable us to supply you with the goods, services and information which you have requested;
  * ensure that content from the website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
  * analyse the information we collect so that we can administer, support and improve and develop the website;
  * provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, unless you have indicated otherwise; and
  * notify you about changes to our service.

We may contact you by post, telephone or fax as well as by email and text message. If you change your mind about being contacted in the future by any of these means then please let us know by [getting in touch with us](http://www.eurostemcell.org/contact).

### Storage of your information

Transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of data transmitted to the website.  Any transmission is at your own risk.  Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to prevent unauthorised access.

### Passwords

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of the website, you are responsible for keeping this password safe and confidential.  You must not share a password with anyone.

### Disclosure of your information

We will not share, sell or distribute any of the information you provide to us without your consent, except where disclosure is:

  * necessary to enforce our rights, including under our website [Terms and Conditions](http://www.eurostemcell.org/terms-and-conditions) of use; or
  * required or permitted by law.

Authorised personnel within the University will be able to access the information you provide to us.  We may also disclose your information to other third parties who act for us for the purposes set out in the policy.

### Outside the European Economic Area

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA").  It may also be processed by staff or by other third parties operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers, agents, or partners.  By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing.

Please note that countries outside the European Economic Area do not always have the same data protection obligations as we do.  However, we will take steps to ensure that your information is used by third parties securely and in accordance with the terms of this privacy policy.

## Our use of cookies

**We use several types of cookies for a range of reasons across the website.  Some are essential, while others you can opt out of or block.  Opting out or blocking some cookies may affect the functionality of the website.**

### Why and how we use cookies

Like many websites, we sometimes place small data files on your computer. These files are known as cookies.

They improve things by:

  * remembering settings, so you don’t have to keep re-entering them whenever you visit a new page
  * recognising that you may already have given a username and password so you don't need to do it for every web page requested
  * measuring how you use the website so we can make sure it meets your needs

These cookies are placed on your device either by EuroStemCell or by the third parties whose services we use as part of the website.

Some cookies are retained in your browser for only as long as you visit our website, while others persist for a longer specified or unspecified period.

### How to block cookies

You can restrict or block cookies which are set during your use of the website by changing your browser’s settings.  Some pages may not work if you completely disable cookies, but many third party cookies can be safely blocked.

Check information in your browser’s help section for specific instructions on how to manage cookies.  Alternatively, websites such as [All About Cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) provide comprehensive guidance.

### Strictly necessary cookies

Some cookies we place on your browser ensure that the website delivers you information and services securely and optimally. You must accept these cookies to be able to make use of our online systems.

Name | Purpose | Typical content | Expires  
---|---|---|---  
SESSxxxID | Authentication session to prevent having to login multiple times in one browser session. | A unique id that ties the current session to a database settings table | One week  
has_js | This helps the website understand browser Javascript functionality | An on/off flag that denotes whether or not the browser supports Javascript | On site exit  

### Performance cookies

We use Google Analytics to monitor visitor behaviour on our website and help us improve our information and services. Anonymous data about your visit is collected and amalgamated with that of other visitors so we can better understand how people use our website.

You can opt out of providing us with this information if you wish, with no impact on your experience of our website - [opt out of Google Analytics](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

Provider | Name | Purpose | More info  
---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics | _utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz | These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. | [Google Privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en_uk/policies/privacy/)  

### Third party cookies

Some website pages use third party services or software such as maps, online videos or social networking features. Many of these services may set cookies on your device. Here are some examples, with links to find out more about their privacy policies:

Provider | Name | Purpose | More info  
---|---|---|---  
Facebook | datr  
lu  
csm | Used by Facebook to managing the Facebook content display on this site, ie the Like button | [Facebook cookies information](https://www.facebook.com/help/?page=176591669064814)  
   
YouTube | SID, LOGIN_INFO, use_hotbox, PREF, SSID, HSID, watched_video_id_list, __utma, __utmz, demographics, VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE | Google sets a number of cookies on any page that includes a Youtube video. While we have no control over the cookies set by Google, they appear to include a mixture of pieces of information to measure the number and behaviour of Youtube users, including information that links your visits to our website with your Google account if you are signed in to one. Information about your use of our website, including your IP address, may be transmitted to Google and stored on servers in the United States.This cookie does not identify you personally unless you are logged into Google, in which case it is linked to your Google account. | [Google's Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)  
  
You can block or remove these third party cookies by altering the settings of your browser. Blocking these cookies is unlikely to impact on your experience of our website.
